

Akshat Gupta

Developer Evangelist

I'm a Software Developer experienced in Frontend Web Development, Cloud Computing, SEO, Digital Marketing, SEM & Offline Marketing.

When I am not coding, I am organising or taking part in workshops, webinars & hackathons, writing blogs, solving doubts and mentoring students.

akshatvg23@gmail.com



Chennai, India

linkedin.com/in/akshatvg

github.com/akshatvg

akshatvg.medium.com

+91 9600093179



www.akshatvg.com



twitter.com/akshatvg



stackoverflow.com/users/11494538/akshat-gupta



instagram.com/akshatvg

EDUCATION

University

Vellore Institute of Technology, Vellore

06/2018 - Present

Information Technology

High School

Chinmaya Vidyalaya, Taylors Road

06/2004 - 06/2018

PCMC

WORK EXPERIENCE

Developer Evangelist Intern

<u>Agora</u>

06/2021 - Present

Tasks:

- Responsible for making various ad-hoc projects.
- Writing technical tutorial blogs.
- Conducting workshops teaching web development and showing how the Agora SDK can be used.
- Solving customer queries on Slack and Stack Overflow support channels.

Contact: William Du - +1 (443) 345-6242

Software Development Intern Josh Talks

06/2020 - Present Tasks:

- Incharge of making the Josh Skills web portal to improve the brand's organic reach for their courses.
- Incharge of maintaining Josh Skills, Josh Kosh and Digital Beti.
- Incharge of managing junior interns, delegating work and coordinating with all teams.

Contact: Harsh Gupta - +91 9811159680

LANGUAGES

English

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Hindi

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Tamil

Limited Working Proficiency

SKILLS

Web Development

Cloud Computing

SEO/SEM

Digital Marketing

Management

WordPress

INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

Public Speaking

Leadership

Teamwork

Time Management

Adaptability Event Management

PROJECTS

Road to DEVSOC (03/2021 - 04/2021)

• Official landing page for Road to DEVSOC 21.

Common Entry Test (12/2020 - 01/2021)

- One stop solution to make club and chapter recruitments in VIT simpler and hassle free.
- This project was used by over 17 clubs, teams and chapters in 2020 with over 70,000 page views and 3,000+ unique users.

Digital Beti (02/2020 - 12/2020)

· Web portal for DigitalBeti, a joint initiative by Facebook and the Government of India to overcome the digital gender gap in India by training women from rural areas to become entrepreneurs, using digital tools.

Josh Skills (06/2020 - 07/2020)

 Mobile first website for Josh Skills with an aim to improve the brand's SEO & online presence for their online courses.

ORGANIZATIONS

CodeChef-VIT (12/2018 - 06/2021)

Technical Chair

Team FootBrawlers (10/2019 - 06/2021)

Management Lead

Microsoft (07/2019 - 06/2021)

Microsoft Learn Student Ambassador

DSC VIT (12/2018 - 10/2020)

Inner Circle Member

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend Web Development

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, MaterializeCSS, ReactJS, Zurb Foundation, JSON, AJAX, Axios and Redux.

Cloud Computing

Azure, Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Heroku and Amazon Web Services (AWS).

Marketing

SEO, SEM, Social Media Marketing, Offline Marketing.

Backend Web Development

PHP and basics of NodeJS & Django.

Competitive Coding

JavaScript, Python, C++, Java.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Second Place (DEVSPACE 2021) (03/2021)

Won the Second Place in the Industrial Collaborations by Dyte track out of 1,414 registered users.

Third Place (WomenTechies 2021) (03/2021)

Won the Second Runner Up award in this women-centric hackathon out of around 380 registered users.

First Place (VIT Hack 2020) (10/2020)

Won the first place in the Gravitas AI Case partner problem statement as well as the AWS Educate open challenge out of over 1,200 registered participants.

Achiever Award & Special Achiever Award (09/2020)

Awarded the Achiever Award & Special Achiever Award for exemplary performance at various National & International events and in recognition of my academic performance.

Audience's Favourite (RTE Hack 2020) (09/2020)

Won the Audience's Favourite Award by being the top voted and most liked project of the hackathon.

Best Healthcare Hack (Hophacks Fall 2019) (09/2019)

Won the best Healthcare Hack award powered by Siemens Healthineers out of 44 submitted projects.

CERTIFICATIONS

Google Cloud Platform Business Professional Accreditation (11/2020 - Present)

Credential ID: 63280081

Google Cloud Platform Fundamentals: Core Infrastructure (05/2019 - Present)

Credential ID: 7PLZLGHTCPFZ

Essential Google Cloud Infrastructure: Foundation (02/2021 - Present)

Credential ID: LGT29UQ8TT8L

Essential Google Cloud Infrastructure: Core Services (02/2021 - Present)

Credential ID: 7GRE2XB43TCG

Elastic Google Cloud Infrastructure: Scaling and Automation (02/2021 - Present)

Credential ID: WSEU3QHHJPCW

Reliable Google Cloud Infrastructure: Design and Process (02/2021 - Present)

Credential ID: 4G3PTX7RJVCS

The Fundamentals of Digital Marketing (07/2020 - Present)

Credential ID: 7PLZLGHTCPFZ

Google Analytics for Beginners (01/2021 - 01/2024)

Advanced Google Analytics (01/2021 - 01/2024)

Google Analytics for Power Users (01/2021 - 01/2024)

Getting Started With Google Analytics 360 (01/2021 - 01/2024)

Introduction to Data Studio (01/2021 - 01/2024)

Google Tag Manager Fundamentals (01/2021 - 01/2024)

Python (Basic) (09/2020 - Present)

Credential ID: B7D22892D983